もし　お女中
どうなされた？
You there, maiden.
What's the matter?
うぅ…。
うわぁ～！！　ひぃ！
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
どうなすったい？　お客さん。
What's wrong, mister?
で…　出やがったんだ。
I-It appeared!
出たって何が？
What appeared?
追いはぎかい？
辻斬りかい？
A highwayman? A slasher wanting
to try out their new sword?
近頃は物騒だからね。
There have been so many
disturbances lately.
そうじゃねえんだよ。
No.
I-It was a… It's a faceless…
の…　のっぺらぼうが！
のっぺらぼう？
ソイツは…。
What? Faceless?
You mean…
Faceless like this?
（ヤマト）こんな顔かね？
（ナルト）ひゃあ～！！
アハハハハ！　ごめん　ごめん
それは　僕の木遁分身だ。
Sorry, sorry.
That's my Wood Clone.
ヤマト隊長　懲りすぎだってばよ。
Captain Yamato, that's going too far.
うわぁ～！！
それにしても　ナルトは怖がりだな。
Still, Naruto.
You're such a scaredy cat.
ヤマト隊長の顔が
いちばん心臓に悪い。
Captain Yamato,
your face is bad for my heart.
（ヤマト）そうむくれるな　ナルト。
Don't be so upset, Naruto.
こう霧がひどくては
他にすることもないしね。
The fog's so thick,
there's nothing else to do.
Yeah, but a grown man like you
telling ghost stories?
だからって　いい大人が怪談なんて
どうかしてると思うな　俺。
Something’s wrong with you!
（アオバ）お前が怖がりすぎなんだって
だから。
You're so easy to scare.
That's why.
俺は　その話
ちっとも怖くなんかねえってばよ。
Stories like that don't
scare me one bit.
ほう　そういうことなら
とっておきの話をしよう。
Okay then,
I'll tell you the best one yet.
こんな日には　あれが出るって
聞いたことがあるんだ。
I've heard that it appears
on days like this.
あれ？
Huh? "It"?
（ヤマト）それは　死者の魂を導く
カラスの先導で現れる。
It appears, led in by black crows that
guide the souls of dead men.
マストに灯した巨大な鬼火が
そいつの証し。
A giant friar's lantern
that lights the mast
confirms its presence.
深い深い霧は　死者の魂。
The thick, thick fog embodies
the souls of dead people.
When you encounter it,
出会ったが最後
死者の国への船旅が始まる。
the final journey to
the land of the dead begins.
それが　幽霊船だ。
That is…
the ghost ship.
死者の魂？
Souls of dead people?
あっ　まさか　この霧。
D-Don't tell me this fog…
そう　こんな霧の中から
幽霊船が現れるのさ。
Yes. The ghost ship appears
out of fog like this.
な～んてね
幽霊船なんて古い迷信さ。
Just kidding. A ghost ship is
just an old superstition.
ヘヘ　だよな
そんなのいるわけねえもんな。
I thought so.
Of course, there's no such thing.
俺ってば
ちっとも信じてなかったってばよ。
I didn't believe you for a second.
へえ　そうは見えなかったけどね。
You could've fooled me.
風が動いた。
The wind just picked up.
何なんだ？
What was that?!
あっ！
これは…。
This is…
幽霊船！？
A ghost ship?!
そんな　まさか…。
No way. It can’t be!
The Cursed Ghost Ship
マジかよ　幽霊船に乗り込むなんて
冗談じゃねえってばよ。
You've got to be kidding!
Are you seriously gonna
board a ghost ship?!
Naruto, there's no such thing
as a ghost ship.
ナルト　幽霊船なんてものは
この世に存在しない。
There sure is. Look at that.
あるじゃねえか　あそこに　ほら！
全部　ヤマト隊長の
言ってたとおりだってばよ。
It's exactly how
Captain Yamato described it.
確かに　うさんくさい船だが→
It's definitely
a suspicious-looking ship,
航海法で　難破船を→
but marine laws dictate that
lost ships must not be left ignored.
そのままにしておくわけには
いかないんだ。
早く調査を済ませれば→
The sooner we check it out,
the sooner we can get back
to our boat.
それだけ早く船に
戻れるということだ。
So give it up.
あきらめるんだな。
こんなことなら　ゲキマユ先生の
つきそいでもしてたほうが→
If that's the case,
I should have stayed back
with Bushy Brow Sensei.
まだ　マシだった。
（ガイ）ナルト　ガッツだぞ！
Naruto, it's all about guts!
ガッツさえあれば　幽霊だろうと
なんだろうと…。
As long as you have guts,
ghosts or whatever are…
船酔いぐらい
ガッツで克服しろっての！
It's only seasickness.
Get over it with guts.
なぁ　アオバのおっちゃん…。
Right, Aoba?
W-Wait a minute.
ちょっと待って…！
お～い　おっちゃん　ヤマト隊長。
Hey Aoba… Captain Yamato…
（ヒシャク）ああ　忙しい　忙しい！
Man, I'm so busy, busy, busy.
なぁ。
Hey…
俺の顔は床じゃねえぞ　こら！
My face isn't the floor. Hey.
忙しい　忙しい！
So busy, so busy.
Wow.
待てよ！
Hey, wait!
So busy, so busy!
忙しい　忙しい！
おいって！　ホント忙しいヤツだな。
H-Hey!
He really is a busy guy.
へぇ　それで船を操るのか。
Oh… So that's how you
operate the ship.
Hey, you've really made
good use of this brush.
おっ　何だ　ずいぶん
使い込んだブラシだったんだな。
触るなよ！
Don't touch it!
The captain gave it to me.
It's very precious to me.
それはな　船長からもらった
大切なものなんだ！
わ…　わかったよ。
O-Okay, I get it.
でも　オメエ　ガキのくせに
メチャクチャ働き者なんだな。
For a young kid,
you really work hard.
１人じゃ大変だろ？
Isn't it hard all by yourself?
よっしゃ　俺も手伝うってばよ！
All right! I'll help you!
１人より２人！
Two is better than one.
２人より大勢でやったほうが
早く終わるってもんだ。
In fact, a bunch of us will finish
much faster than just two!
それに　オメエの
仕事が終わんねえと→
After all, I don't think I'll get to talk
to you unless you finish your work.
話を聞いて
もらえそうにないからな。
どりゃ～っ！
Boy, am I tired.
あ～　疲れた。
お兄ちゃん。
あ？　俺は　ナルトってんだ。
Say brother…
Huh? My name's Naruto.
ナルト　俺　ヒシャク。
Naruto… I'm Hishaku.
おう　よろしくな！
Nice to meet you.
ナルトは　忍者だったんだな。
強いのか？
You're a ninja, Naruto?
Are you strong?
ヘヘン　あったりめえよ！
Of course, I'm strong.
I'm aiming to become the Hokage.
これでも火影を
目指してるんだぜ。
火影？
ああ。
The Hokage?
Yup! The strongest and
most important ninja in the village.
里でいちばん強くて
偉い忍ってことだ。
なんだ　それなら火影ってのより
船長のほうがすごいよ。
Is that all?
Well, my captain is even greater
than your Hokage.
なっ　なに！？
W-What?!
The captain is strong and
not just important.
船長は
強くて偉いだけじゃなくって→
優しくて仲間思いなんだ。
He's kind and considerate of others.
俺も　いつか船長になるんだ！
I'm gonna become
a captain too one day!
H-Hold it!
いや　ちょ　ちょっと待て！
My Hokage is strong and
important and kind,
火影は　強くて　偉くて　優しくて
仲間思いだけじゃなくって→
and not just considerate,
but generous.
気前がよくって　え～と
それから　あ～　それから。
And…and…
い～や　船長！
No, my captain is!
火影！
船長！
The Hokage!
The captain!
火影だ！
船長！
The Hokage!
The captain!
ハハッ！
アハハ！
お互い目指してるものが
あるんだな。
So we both have something
we're aiming for.
うん。
そうだ　あれ教えてくれよ。
By the way, teach me that thing.
あれ？
That thing?
The way you tapped the brush earlier.
ほら　さっきのブラシの
タンタンって叩くヤツ。
なかなか　かっこよかったぜ。
That was cool.
あれは船長に教わったんだ。
The captain taught it to me.
このブラシも
船長からもらったんだよ。
The captain gave me
this brush too.
ふ～ん。
Can we join in your conversation?
（ヤマト）僕らも　話に
まぜてもらっていいかな？
あちこち回ったけど→
I looked around,
but it's just an ordinary ship
on the inside, Captain Yamato.
中は　ごく普通の船だったぜ
ヤマト隊長。
やっぱ
幽霊船じゃないんじゃねえの？
It's not a ghost ship.
アハハ　幽霊船だって
そんなの迷信に決まってるよ。
A ghost ship?
That's just a superstition.
But…
だけど　あれってば
人魂じゃなかったのか？
Isn't that made up of human souls?
マストの炎？
あれは船乗りの間じゃ→
You mean the glow on the mast?
Well, among sailors, it's supposed
to be a sign of good luck.
幸運のしるしって
言われているものでさ。
静電気が
光って見えてるだけだよ。
That's just static electricity discharging.
せ　静電気？
S-Static electricity?
じゃあ　マストのカラスは？
普通　カラスなんて海にいねえぞ。
Then what about the crows on the mast?
You don't normally find crows
on the ocean.
あれは　カラスじゃないよ。
Those aren't crows.
羽を休めている海鳥が
煙突のススで汚れただけ。
They're just seabirds taking a rest.
They’re dirty from the ash coming
from the smokestack.
マジかよ。
Really?
さあ　幽霊船の話は
おいておくとして→
Putting aside talk about a ghost ship,
僕たちも　船の中を
調べさせてもらったが→
we took the liberty of checking
the inside of this ship too.
この船には　キミ以外の乗組員が
いないようだね。
It seems there are no other sailors
on board besides you.
他の乗組員は
どうしたんだい？
What happened to them?
このクラスの船となると→
A ship this class requires
quite a few deckhands.
それなりの人数が
必要なはずだが。
そういや
ブラシの船長もいねえな。
That's right.
Where's the captain who
gave you the brush?
うん　いたよ　仲間たちが。
Yeah.
I used to have shipmates.
何かあったようだね。
I presume something happened.
海には　幽霊船なんて
バカな迷信なんかよりも→
Under the sea,
lurks something
even more terrifying
よっぽど恐ろしいものが
潜んでいるんだ。
than some stupid superstition
about a ghost ship.
アイツだ！
アイツ？
It’s here!
It?
ああ　そうだ
伝説の海のバケモノ　ムクロオオガニだよ！
Oh yes.
The legendary sea monster,
the Skeleton Crab!
カニ？
違う！　ただのカニなんかじゃない！
Crab?
It's not an ordinary crab!
小さな島ぐらいある
大きなヤツなんだ！
It's huge, the size of a small island.
甲羅は頑丈だし
でっかいハサミに囚われたら最後→
Its shell is rock hard
and if you get caught between
its pinchers, it's over.
どんなものでも
粉々にされちゃう！
It can pulverize anything!
それに　甲羅に寄生したフジツボは
生きたまま　人を食らうんだ。
And the barnacles that are
attached on the shell
devour humans alive!
船長も　他のみんなも
みんな　みんな…　アイツに。
The captain and the rest of
the crew…
They were all killed by it.
ナルト！　忍って強いんだろ？
Naruto! Ninja are strong, right?
アイツのことやっつけて
船長たちの敵をとってくれよ！
Please destroy it and avenge
the captain and the others!
うわっ！
隊長！
あぁ～っ！
Captain!
Oh no…
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
♪～
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
♪～
あぁ…　アイツが　また！
That thing’s gonna…
心配すんな　ヒシャク！
俺が　アイツをぶっ飛ばしてやる！
Leave it to me, Hishaku!
I'll crush that thing!
アオバのおっちゃん！
ヒシャクと一緒に　船に戻って→
Aoba, take Hishaku back to
the ship with you!
And let everyone know about this.
みんなに　このことを
知らせてくれってばよ！
But…
しかし…。
迷ってるヒマなんかねえよ！
We don't have time to
stand around and think!
ヤマト隊長を助けて
バケモンガニをとめる役か→
One of us has to save Captain Yamato
and stop that monster crab,
船の仲間に
このことを知らせる役か→
or notify the others on the ship.
どっちかを
２人がやんなきゃなんねえ！
Each of us has to do one task.
俺よか　アオバのおっちゃんのほうが
冷静に伝えられるだろ！
You probably can explain things
to the others
more calmly than me, Aoba.
フンッ　頼もしくなったものだ。
He's become so reliable.
わかった！　その役は
俺が引き受けよう！
Okay, I'll take on that job.
Naruto, aren't you scared?
ナルト…　怖くないの？
あんな　バケモノ相手にするなんて！
How can you take on that monster?
I told you.
言っただろ！
俺は　火影を目指してんだ！
I'm aiming to become
the Hokage some day.
仲間のためなら
ちっとも怖くなんてねえってばよ。
If it's for my comrades,
I'm not afraid of anything.
仲間のため…。
For your comrades…
((ヒシャク！　お前は　まだ幼い。
Hishaku… You're still young.
せめて　お前だけでも
助かってくれ！
You must live.
怖いよ　船長…。
I'm scared, Captain!
船長も一緒に。
Please stay with me, Captain.
こいつは　俺が　この船に
乗り込んだときからのつきあいだ。
I've had this from the time
I joined this ship.
さぁ　こいつを持っててくれ。
Take this.
えっ！？
この　すり減ったブラシが
俺の魂だ。
Those worn-down bristles
carry my soul in them.
お前が持っててくれれば
俺も安心なんだよ。
If you take it,
I'll know it's in good hands.
船長…。
Captain!
俺には　まだ仕事が残ってる。
I still have work to do.
It's my job to stay with
my ship until the end,
俺を信じて　ついてきてくれた
仲間のためにも→
for the sake of my comrades who
believed in me and stayed with me.
船の最後を見届けるっていう
仕事がな。
(それが船長ってもんだ))
That's the duty of a ship's captain.
Just you wait.
I'll get revenge for you!
待ってろよ　俺が　オメエの敵
とってきてやっからな！
あれが木ノ葉の里を救った英雄
うずまきナルトだ。
That's Naruto Uzumaki,
the hero who saved
the Hidden Leaf Village.
うずまきナルト…。
Naruto Uzumaki.
さぁ行こう　俺たちの船に。
Let's get back to our ship.
You good-for-nothing…
Going around threatening everyone!
この野郎　脅かしやがって！
お化けじゃなけりゃ→
If you're not a ghost,
then you don't scare me one bit!
お前なんかちっとも
怖くねえんだよ！
Rasengan!
螺旋丸！
クソッ　さすがバケモンガニ
甲羅は硬ぇってばよ。
Damn! That monster crab has
a hard shell, all right!
This thing… It's not only strong,
but it's fast too.
コイツ　頑丈なだけじゃねえ。
意外に素早いぞ。
アオバ　俺も船も大揺れだ。
いったい　どうした？
Aoba, our ship is swaying badly.
What's going on?
We have to get out of
this area immediately.
急いで　この海域から
脱出しなければなりません。
Naruto is buying us
some time right now.
今　ナルトがその時間を
稼いでくれているんです。
船長　俺に勇気を！
Captain… Grant me the courage.
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
《大技で勝負ってわけには
いかねえか》
I can't do anything big to settle this.
早くヤマト隊長を助けねえと。
I have to save Captain Yamato quickly!
Damn it.
野郎！
やべぇ！
This is bad!
みんな　力を貸して！
Everyone, please lend me
your strength!
♪～
しめた！　ヒシャクがやったのか？
助かった。
They got it.
I wonder if Hishaku did it.
That helped!
ヤマト隊長！
油断した。
Captain Yamato!
I was careless.
こんなのに捕まるとは　面目ない。
いいってばよ。
あっ！
お～い　ナルト！
ヤマト隊長　今だ。
ヤツの甲羅は
とてつもなく硬ぇんだ。
なるほど。　やわらかいところを
狙おうっていうんだね。
木遁の術！
今だ　ナルト！
わかってるってばよ！
ヒシャク　おめえの勇気を貸してくれ。
うん。
覚悟しやがれ　バケモンガニ！
螺旋丸！
やったな　ナルト。
ああ　ヒシャクのおかげだってばよ。
俺より先に
夢　叶えちまったみてえだな。
ちょっとの間だったけどよ
おめえってば→
火影にも負けねえ
立派な船長だったぜ。
ありがとう　ナルト。
俺　ずっと後悔してたんだ。
あのとき　みんなと一緒に
戦えなかったことを。
だから　ナルトが
みんなの敵をとってくれて→
胸のつかえが取れた気分だよ。
よせよ！　バケモンガニを倒せたのは
ヒシャクのおかげだ。
それに　お前ももう
俺たちの仲間だしな。
うん　そうだね。
ん？
でも　もう　さよならだ　ナルト。
お　おい　どうなってんだ？
おい　どこ行ったんだってばよ？
ヒシャク！
誰も　おめえを責めたりしねえよ。
変に責任感が強いから
困ったもんだ。
おめえが成仏しねえから→
俺たちまで
成仏できねえんじゃねえか。
ごめんね　みんな。
なあに　謝ることはないさ。
あのカニ野郎に
体当たりをかましたときにゃ→
俺たちも　スカッとしたぜ。
そのだ　そうだ！
そのとおり！
よし　景気づけに
いつものやつをやるぞ　みんな！
お～！
さよなら　ナルト！
（みんな）達者でな！
ああ　ヒシャク　元気でな！
えっ…　ウソだろう？
うわぁ～！　幽霊船だ！